searchanonymo.com 2017-06-06

# Search Anonymo

In this Privacy Statement we, Search Anonymo (hereinafter referred to as “SMM” or “we” or “us”) inform you (as a natural person or on behalf of a legal person, hereinafter referred to as “You”) of our handling of your personal data with regard to our product websites (hereinafter “Product-Website”) and our free downloadable browser add-ons/extensions/plug-ins (hereinafter “the SMM-Product” or “SMM-Products”), available through the Product-Website or the add-on/extension/plug-in stores of the relevant browser providers and other third party websites.

This Privacy Statement explains what kind of data we collect, how we store and transfer it and how we use it.

Some of the data we collect, either individually or aggregated, may be considered as being personal data. We treat this data as required by the applicable data protection laws.

We will always honor your decisions for how your personal data is used. We have safeguards in place to protect your data from loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration, or destruction.

When we post changes to this Privacy Statement, we will include the date when the Privacy Statement was last updated. If we significantly change this Privacy Statement or how we use your personal information, we will notify You either by prominently posting a notice (e.g. on our Product-Websites) prior to implementing the change or by sending you a notification directly.

We encourage you to review this Privacy Statement periodically, as it is your responsibility to remain informed at all times of any changes to our Privacy Statement.

## 1\. COLLECTION, STORAGE AND USE OF YOUR DATA

a) When You visit a Product-Website, our servers will temporarily save every request in a logfile. The following data are registered and stored by us without any involvement from You:

  * the IP address of the requesting terminal device;
  * the date and time of access;
  * the name and URL of the file called up;
  * the website from which the file is accessed;
  * the operating system of your terminal device and the browser you are using;
  * the name of your internet access provider;

These data are collected and processed with the aim of enabling the Product-Website to be used (connecting to it), guaranteeing long-term system security and stability, enabling the network infrastructure to be administered from a technical viewpoint and to constantly optimize the services; these data are also used for our internal, statistical purposes.

Your IP address will only be evaluated in the event of attacks on our network infrastructure as well - in anonymized form - for statistical purposes and will generally be deleted after 30 days.

In addition, we use cookies and web analysis services when people visit the Product-Website. See section 5 of this Privacy statement for this.

b) When You install and run a SMM-Product, our servers may register and store the following data without any involvement from You:

  * the IP address of the your terminal device;
  * the date and time of the installation of your SMM-Product ;
  * the version no. of your SMM-Product;
  * the name and URL of the file called up;
  * the operating system of your terminal device and the browser you are using;
  * gen. geo-marketing data (city, country-id);

These data are processed and collected to check for existing updates of a SMM-Product and to constantly optimize the performance of the SMM-Products; these data are also used for internal, statistical purposes of SMM.

Your anonymized IP address will only be evaluated for statistical purposes and will be deleted after 30 days.

c) When you perform a internet search through any search features within a SMM-Product and / or through a adjusted web browser´s default homepage and/or default new tab page and/or adjusted default search settings, search results will be provided in cooperation with Yahoo Inc. (“Yahoo”) or Microsoft Corp. (“Microsoft”) or other intermediaries.

When initiating a search query through SMM´s search features, Yahoo as well as Microsoft as well as other intermediaries may collect specific information in order to display the relevant search results. For this purpose, the following data will be recorded:

  * your search keyword;
  * the IP-address of your terminal device;
  * the date and time of your search query;
  * any unique identifiers from any cookies used by Microsoft or Yahoo or others;
  * the the search- and browser settings of your browser;
  * your browser's language-settings;
  * your browser type;

The collected data is transferred to third-party-content-providers and providers of sponsored links. You can find further information on the Yahoo data privacy guidelines in the [Yahoo Privacy Center](https://policies.yahoo.com/us/en/yahoo/privacy/index.htm), and on the Microsoft data privacy guidelines in the [Microsoft Privacy Statement](https://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/privacystatement/).

## 2\. USE OF PERSONAL DATA

Personal data is only collected or processed if You have provided the information voluntarily, e.g. in the context of an enquiry. You may object in writing (e.g. by email) to the storage or use of your personal data with immediate effect. your data is not passed on to third parties, unless such a disclosure is mandatory under statutory provisions.

## 3\. RIGHTS WITH RESPECT TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA

In accordance with current data protection laws You may at any time request in writing (e.g. by email) that we provide information on whether and which personal data about you we have stored. You will receive the appropriate information without undue delay.

To obtain information on your personal data, to ask for incorrect data to be corrected or blocked as well as for more detailed questions on the use of your personal data, please contact:

E-mail: [support@searchanonymo.com](mailto:support@searchanonymo.com)

You can have your personal data deleted at any time. This can be done by sending a corresponding request by e-mail the address above.

## 4\. SECURITY OF YOUR DATA

The personal data you make available to us is secured by application of all technical and organisational security measures to ensure that it is inaccessible to unauthorised third parties.

## 5\. WEBSITE ANALYTICS

( **Google Analytics** ) Our Product-Websites use the web analysis service Google Analytics by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. In order to deactivate Google Analytics Google provides a browser plug-in at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>. Google Analytics uses cookies. Cookies are small text files which enable the storing of specific, user-related information on the user’s terminal. This enables analysis of the use of our website provision by Google. The information generated by the cookie about use of our Product-Websites (including your IP address) will usually be transmitted to and stored by Google on a server in the United States.

Please note that on our Product-Websites Google Analytics has been extended with the code “gat._anonymizeIp();” to guarantee the anonymised collection of IP addresses (IP masking). Where anonymisation is activated Google will shorten IP addresses within the member states of the European Union and other states participating in the Agreement on the European Economic Area, which makes any identification of individuals impossible. Only in exceptional cases will a full IP address be transmitted to a Google server in the USA and be shortened there.

Google uses the collected information to analyse use of our Product-Websites, compile reports for us in this regard and perform other related services for us. Find out more at:  
<http://www.google.com/intl/de/analytics/privacyoverview.html>.

( **piwik** ) For the statistical analysis of user visits our Product-Websites use the open source software Piwik ([www.piwik.org](http://www.piwik.org/)). Data collected via Piwik is used in anonymised format in order to analyse and improve use of our website. IP addresses are collected in Piwik, but only in anonymised format. Piwik is used without cookies being set.

You may prevent data collection by Piwik by activating the “Do not track” function in your browser. In most browsers, this function can be found in  
“Settings -> Data protection”.

You will have full use of our websites even if the “Do not track” function is enabled. Piwik will in this case only be notified by your browser that the user does not wish to be tracked. Enabling the “Do not track” function may lead to restrictions in the use of other websites.

## 6\. SOCIAL PLUGINS

Social plugins for various online social networks (e.g. Facebook, Twitter, Google+, YouTube and Pinterest) may be integrated into our Product-Websites. These allow you to place bookmarks on these sites and share them with other members of the online social networks. You can recognize social plugins by means of the logos that can be seen on the websites of the online social networks.

If You call up a Product-Website containing these social plugins, a direct connection is established with the servers of the online social network and from there the plugin image (which is now visible to You) and associated functions are communicated directly to your browser, which integrates them into the layout of our Product-Website. If You are logged into the online social network under your username and password at this point, the fact that You are visiting our Product-Website is communicated to said network and information to this effect can be assigned to your user account.

When You interact with the social plugins, for example if You share one of our Product-Websites or use the Facebook "Like" or "Share", the Pinterest "Pin It" or the Twitter "Tweet This" function, the content of our Product-Website will be linked with your profile within the online social network. If You are not a member of the online social network or have logged out from these providers before visiting our Product-Website, there is still a possibility that at least your IP address will be communicated and stored there. Further processing within the connected online social networks, storage time and intended use are defined exclusively by these providers.

The following links give You more detailed information on the social plugins used and the data protection notices of these providers.

Social Plugin| Operator of the online social network| Data protection declaration of the online social network  
---|---|---  
Facebook Like / Share Button| Facebook, Inc., 1601 South California AvenuePalo Alto, CA 94304, USA| [www.facebook.com/about/privacy/](http://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/)  
Twitter Tweet This Button| Twitter, Inc., 795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA| [twitter.com/privacy](http://twitter.com/privacy)  
Pin-It Button| Pinterest Inc., 635 High Street, Palo Alto, CA, 94301, USA| [pinterest.com/about/privacy/](http://pinterest.com/about/privacy/)  
Google+ Button| Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA| [www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
Youtube Button| Google Inc., Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA| [www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)  
  
If You do not want social networks to collect details about You through active plug-ins, You can either deactivate the social plug-ins with a simple click on our Product-Website or select the "Disable third-party cookies" function in your browser settings. The browser will then not send any cookies to the server in the case of content embedded by other suppliers. However, with this setting it is possible that other cross-domain functions also will not work besides the plug-ins.

## 7\. CONTACT DETAILS

You can contact SMM at any time on data protection matters as follows:

Search Anonymo  
244 5th Avenue Suite C12  
New York, NY  
NY 100001 USA  
E-Mail: support@searchanonymo.com  

## 8\. ACTUALITY OF PRIVACY STATEMENT

This Privacy Statement is the most current version from 23/01/2017.
